<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Alphonse and Lucy Griffith Paré Foundation</title>
    <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://parefoundation.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominican Republic</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/dominican_republic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/dominican_republic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Dominican Republic, we supported Charlene for her early elementary education. She attended an international school where she developed her love of learning and gained a lot of confidence socially. However, after 3rd grade, the administrators of the school and her parents agreed that it would be best for her fluency in Spanish to transfer her to a Spanish public school. As a result, she no longer needed the support of the Paré Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Dominican_Republic/Charlene.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Charlene&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malawi</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/malawi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/malawi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-jim-and-nancy-wright-scholars&#34;&gt;The Jim and Nancy Wright Scholars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Led and managed by Antoinette Holland, the Foundation’s agent in Malawi, the program is focused on providing youth, and especially girls, the opportunity to continue their education in secondary school despite their lack of resources.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jim and Nancy Wright Scholars Program (named in recognition of the Wright family’s long-term support of Antoinette (Toni) Holland’s work, and to honour Jim’s memory) continues to be the cornerstone of the Foundation’s activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the nature of schooling in Sub-Saharan Africa, the chosen approach continues to be holistically supporting beneficiaries, covering both direct and indirect costs of education: tuition fees, textbooks, school supplies, mid-day meals, and transportation costs, if need be. This last item is particularly important when supporting girls’ education, given their vulnerability when traveling long distances in remote areas. In addition, students are guaranteed continued support throughout their secondary education, conditional upon satisfactory academic achievement. We are currently supporting 8 students in secondary school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/ricebags.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rice&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the Wright Scholars that have graduated from secondary school, 7 have gone on to university and been able to count on continued support from the Foundation. We are currently supporting 5 university students: Esau is at Polytechnic University finishing a Bachelor of Science in Land Survey; Jacqueline is at LUNA (Lilongwe University of Agriculture Research) in her last year of a Bachelor of Science in Development Economics; Isabel is studying Earth Science at MUST (Malawi University of Science and Technology); Naomi is at St-Joseph&amp;rsquo;s College of Nursing; and Benson is enrolled in a program to become an electrician.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  

  
  
  
  
  
    
      
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; data-caption=&#34;Esau&#34; href=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Esau.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Esau.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
      
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; data-caption=&#34;Jacqueline&#34; href=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Jacqueline.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Jacqueline.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
      
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; data-caption=&#34;Jane&#34; href=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Jane%20Chiona.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Jane%20Chiona.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;loyola-jesuit-secondary-school&#34;&gt;Loyola Jesuit Secondary School&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re very pleased to announce our new partnership with &lt;a href=&#34;https://loyola-malawi.org/&#34;&gt;Loyola-Malawi&lt;/a&gt;, launched in memory of Donald Paré, former President of the Paré Foundation, who was deeply committed to the Foundation’s mission, as well as the Jesuit ideal of forming “Women and Men for Others”. Starting in 2020-21, we welcome our first cohort of 5 Paré scholars: four girls, one boy. We are committed to supporting these five students every year through to high school graduation, and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loyola-Malawi is situated in Kasungu district, a few hours north of Lilongwe, the capital. The school boasts beautiful grounds and a new building to welcome its students. Admission is based on merit alone. Run by the Zambia-Malawi Jesuit Province, Loyola strives to offer a ‘preferential option for the poor’* – in this case, high quality education to those that otherwise wouldn’t have access to such schooling. We at the Paré Foundation are thrilled to participate in that mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*The term ‘preferential option for the poor’ is attributed to the Jesuits of Latin America, in the 1960s.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/canada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tannis&#34;&gt;Tannis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Paré Foundation supported Tannis, an Indiginous woman, in the completion of her Bachelor of Law from the University of Saskatchewan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Canada/tannis.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tannis&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After graduating in June 2020 amidst the Covid-19 pandemic, Tannis opted to remain in Saskatoon. Going forward, she aims to help alleviate the over representation of Indigenous children in government care. She will be working to help Indigenous communities to implement Bill C-92 which will allow them to direct their own policies to ensure that their children remain within their respective families and communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haiti</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/haiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/haiti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In partnership with the Haitian Education and Leadership Program (HELP), the Foundation has set up a Paré Scholar Program to support deserving young students in Haiti.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started in 2010, shortly after the earthquake, the Paré scholar program consists of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuition-free classes at an internationally accredited university&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Textbooks and supplies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Housing in HELP dorms and a living stipend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic advising and counseling, including computer literacy and English classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership &amp;amp; Citizenship training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on HELP&amp;rsquo;s program, click &lt;a href=&#34;http://uhelp.net/our-story/how-we-work/#sthash.ZRikysiZ.dpuf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our current Paré Scholar, Valencia Dorvilus, is studying agro-economics at Quisqueya University in Port-au-Prince. Her classes include botany, soil science and local traditional medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Haiti/valenciaD.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Valencia&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to financial support from the Jind family in Toronto, we&amp;rsquo;ve been able to significantly expand our partnership with HELP. Valencia will be joined by two more scholars, as the Paré Foundation-HELP partnership grows from 1 to 3 scholars over the next 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our collaboration with the Regenboog Foundation continues in Tiruvannamalai where the Paré Foundation has the honour of supporting three new students: Keerthiga (Computer Science), Sakthivel (Chemistry), Abitha (Commerce).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in 2021, Muthazhagi completed her Master&amp;rsquo;s Degree in Medical Physics. Her sister, Vasanthazhagi, also supported by the Paré Foundation, is in her second year of a bachelor in Information Technology. Gayathri (pictured below) is in her 4th year of nursing. She is already hard at work helping with the vaccination effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/India/Gayathri.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gayathri&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/canada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mohawk-language-preservation&#34;&gt;Mohawk Language Preservation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2020, the Paré Foundation supports a Mohawk language program at Kanehsatà:ke, Quebec. The multi-year adult immersion program is offered by the Mohawk Language Custodian Association of Kanehsatà:ke and is designed to ensure the ancestral language survives and flourishes. The program has now graduated its first four students. All have found local employment, including jobs in health services and education, as well as a position as an announcer at Kanehsatà:ke’s radio station, RKR-FM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of these adult students have no income stream or financial support to cover living expenses during their training. Any help is greatly appreciated. The Paré Foundation helps provide the support they need to achieve teaching proficiency in Mohawk. Students from this program will one day replace the last two current (very elderly) teachers at Kanehsatà:ke Elementary and High School.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Canada/MLP.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mohawk Language Custodian Association&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
