<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Alphonse &amp; Lucy Griffith Paré Foundation</title>
    <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://parefoundation.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malawi</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/malawi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/malawi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-jim-and-nancy-wright-scholars&#34;&gt;The Jim and Nancy Wright Scholars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Led and managed by Antoinette Holland, the Foundation’s agent in Malawi, the program is focused on providing youth, and especially girls, the opportunity to continue their education despite their lack of resources.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jim and Nancy Wright Scholars Program (named in recognition of the Wright family’s long-term support of Antoinette (Toni) Holland’s work, and to honour Jim’s memory) continues to be the model on which new Paré Foundation projects are based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the nature of schooling in Sub-Saharan Africa, the chosen approach is to holistically support beneficiaries, covering both direct and indirect costs of education: tuition fees, textbooks, school supplies, mid-day meals, and transportation costs, if need be. This last item is particularly important when supporting girls’ education, given their vulnerability when traveling long distances in remote areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Tamandani25.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tamandani&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Judith25.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Judith&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The high school students we supported are now all enrolled in university:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tamandani and Judith (pictured above) are headed into their third year at Kamuzu University of Health Sciences, for Bachelors degrees in Science of Nutrition and Dietetics and Biomedical Science, respectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jane (pictured below) is headed into her last year of a bachelor of Arts at the University of Malawi in Zomba studying Media for Development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Jane.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jane&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;loyola-jesuit-secondary-school&#34;&gt;Loyola Jesuit Secondary School&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our seventh year working in partnership with Loyola-Malawi, in memory of Donald Paré, former President of the Paré Foundation, who was deeply committed to the Foundation’s mission, as well as the Jesuit ideal of forming “Women and Men for Others”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our current group of five students &amp;ndash; all girls &amp;ndash; are in their 3rd year of high school. Despite the many challenges Malawi has endured over the past year, all five students managed to successfully complete Form 2 and are now advancing to Form 3. All five of them also passed the National Junior Certificate of Education exams this year. Our support gives these girls from disadvantaged backgrounds access to career possibilities that would otherwise have been impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/loyola-Malawi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Loyola&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loyola-Malawi is a Jesuit run school located in Kasungu district, a few hours north of Lilongwe, the capital. The school boasts beautiful grounds and a new building to welcome its students. Admission is based on merit alone. Run by the Zambia-Malawi Jesuit Province, Loyola strives to offer a ‘preferential option for the poor’* – in this case, high quality education to those that otherwise wouldn’t have access to such schooling. We at the Paré Foundation are thrilled to participate in that mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*The term ‘preferential option for the poor’ is attributed to the Jesuits of Latin America, in the 1960s.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominican Republic</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/dominican_republic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/dominican_republic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Dominican Republic, we supported Charlene for her early elementary education. She attended an international school where she developed her love of learning and gained a lot of confidence socially. However, after 3rd grade, the administrators of the school and her parents agreed that it would be best for her fluency in Spanish to transfer her to a Spanish public school. As a result, she no longer needed the support of the Paré Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Dominican_Republic/Charlene.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Charlene&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haiti</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/haiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/haiti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In partnership with the Haitian Education and Leadership Program (HELP), the Foundation has set up a Paré Scholar Program to support deserving young students in Haiti.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started in 2010, shortly after the earthquake, the Paré Scholar program consists of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuition-free classes at an internationally accredited university&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Textbooks and supplies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Housing in HELP dorms and a living stipend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic advising and counseling, including computer literacy and English classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership &amp;amp; Citizenship training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on HELP&amp;rsquo;s program, click &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uhelp.net/our-story&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently supporting two Paré Scholars at HELP: Sabine Joseph (Finance) and Loveline Dieujuste (Management). They are both deeply grateful to HELP for accompanying them in their studies. Academic successes aside, perhaps most important is their commitment to serving their community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loveline, who has been deeply affected by the ongoing violence in Haiti, believes that “…Haiti needs a woman like me who can wipe away her tears.” She hopes for calm to return so that she and her classmates can fully embrace the opportunities before them such as internships, service projects, and group activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Haiti/Loveline.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Loveline&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sabine will be graduating next year and she is already giving back by volunteering in the HELP accounting department. She also finds the time to support her community by giving of her time to a group called Devlopman Reyel which organizes backpack and school supply drives to help parents provide their children with the essentials for a strong start in school. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say things have been easy for her; looking back on the recent months, she confides that &amp;ldquo;I have been stressed, I have been afraid, but I have nevertheless kept the courage to continue. I am aware of my responsibilities and I know that I must face them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Haiti/Sabine.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sabine&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/canada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tannis&#34;&gt;Tannis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Paré Foundation supported Tannis, an Indiginous woman, in the completion of her Bachelor of Law from the University of Saskatchewan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Canada/tannis.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tannis&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After graduating in June 2020 amidst the Covid-19 pandemic, Tannis opted to remain in Saskatoon. She worked to help alleviate the over representation of Indigenous children in government care and she hoped to help Indigenous communities implement Bill C-92 allowing them to direct their own policies to ensure that their children remain within their respective families and communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, Tannis passed away in April 2024. Soon after graduating from law school, Tannis was diagnosed with an incurable cancer which she was fiercely determined to overcome and then bravely accepted. The First Nations name Tannis was given translates to &amp;rsquo;eagle that flies high&amp;rsquo; representing strength, wisdom, courage, and power. She was all of those things and more. Such a loss for so many. She will be missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our collaboration with the Regenboog Foundation continues in Tiruvannamalai where the Paré Foundation is proud to continue supporting Sujatha, a dedicated nursing student in Chennai, who expects to graduate in a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, our sponsorship extends to 150 students across four evening schools, two of which serve children from the marginalized Irula tribal community. We are also delighted to congratulate Madhan Mohan, the founder of Regenboog India, for receiving recognition from the Governor of Tamil Nadu for his outstanding work in the community. This honor is a testament to his tireless commitment to improving the lives of those in need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/B_Z9_h3XsNY&#34;&gt;12-minute video&lt;/a&gt; provides a comprehensive look at the Regenboog Foundation&amp;rsquo;s impactful work in education and community development in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/India/eveningschool3.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Evening School&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/canada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mohawk-language-preservation&#34;&gt;Mohawk Language Preservation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2020, the Paré Foundation supports a Mohawk language program at Kanehsatà:ke, Quebec. The multi-year adult immersion program is offered by the Mohawk Language Custodian Association of Kanehsatà:ke and is designed to ensure the ancestral language survives and flourishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interest in the programme is growing because the graduates are speaking Mohawk (Kanien&amp;rsquo;kéha) in public and on the local radio station. Many are working in the community, at the Health Center, and teaching in the Nursery and Kindergarten immersion programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kawisaienhne Albany is a recent graduate of the adult education program of the Mohawk Language Custodian Association. She is now working as a teacher’s aide and will graduate through the McGill teacher training program as a teacher this coming spring. During an interview this fall, she expressed how the language courses have helped her gain a deep understanding of her culture and language and how she hopes to see it go further. You can hear an excerpt from the interview with Kawisaienhne Albany &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/eVKcWWLchEY&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Foundation is thrilled to see this programme helping to shape and support the community of Kanehsatà:ke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Canada/MohawkMcGillstudents.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Mohawk Language Custodian Association&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;carejeunesse&#34;&gt;CareJeunesse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Canada/carejeunesselogo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CareJeunesse&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Centre Amitié, Ressources, et Entraide pour la Jeunesse (C.A.R.E. Jeunesse) is a Quebec, bilingual, non-profit organization dedicated to providing a community and a voice for youth leaving government care. Founded by alumni of care who have experienced the system first hand, the organization aims to assist youth after they leave care. The Paré Foundation is offering scholarships to two students who need support to continue their education:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shanice is a nursing student at Université du Québec en Abitibi-Témiscamingue. She successfully completed her 2024-25 classes and is currently enrolled in her last semester of courses. In January, she will start her final internship. After she graduates, Shanice plans to work as a nurse in northern Québec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elijah has transferred from the Urban Studies program at Concordia University and enrolled in the Bachelor of Social Work program at McGill. He hopes to enter the combined law and social work graduate program once he finishes his bachelor&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
