<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Alphonse and Lucy Griffith Paré Foundation</title>
    <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://parefoundation.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malawi</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/malawi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/malawi/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Malawi_Flag.png&#34; style=&#34;float:right;width:150px;height:100px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-jim-and-nancy-wright-scholars&#34;&gt;The Jim and Nancy Wright Scholars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Led and managed by Antoinette Holland, the Foundation’s agent in Malawi, the program is focused on providing youth, and especially girls, the opportunity to continue their education in secondary school despite their lack of resources.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jim and Nancy Wright Scholars Program (named in recognition of the Wright family’s long-term support of Antoinette (Toni) Holland’s work, and to honour Jim’s memory) continues to be the cornerstone of the Foundation’s activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the nature of schooling in Sub-Saharan Africa, the chosen approach continues to be holistically supporting beneficiaries, covering both direct and indirect costs of education: tuition fees, textbooks, school supplies, mid-day meals, and transportation costs, if need be. This last item is particularly important when supporting girls’ education, given their vulnerability when traveling long distances in remote areas. In addition, students are guaranteed continued support throughout their secondary education, conditional upon satisfactory academic achievement. We are currently supporting 8 students in secondary school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/ricebags.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rice&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the Wright Scholars that have graduated from secondary school, 7 have gone on to university and been able to count on continued support from the Foundation. We are currently supporting 5 university students: Esau is at Polytechnic University finishing a Bachelor of Science in Land Survey; Jacqueline is at LUNA (Lilongwe University of Agriculture Research) in her last year of a Bachelor of Science in Development Economics; Isabel is studying Earth Science at MUST (Malawi University of Science and Technology); Naomi is at St-Joseph&amp;rsquo;s College of Nursing; and Benson is enrolled in a program to become an electrician.&lt;/p&gt;









  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  

  
  
  
  
  
    
      
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; data-caption=&#34;Esau&#34; href=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Esau.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Esau.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
      
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; data-caption=&#34;Jacqueline&#34; href=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Jacqueline.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Jacqueline.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
      
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; data-caption=&#34;Jane&#34; href=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Jane%20Chiona.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Jane%20Chiona.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominican Republic</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/dominican_republic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/dominican_republic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Dominican_Republic/DR_Flag.png&#34;style=&#34;float=left;width:150px;height:100px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Dominican Republic, we supported Charlene for her early elementary education. She attended an international school where she developed her love of learning and gained a lot of confidence socially. However, after 3rd grade,
the administrators of the school and her parents agreed that it would be best for her fluency in Spanish to transfer her to a Spanish public school. As a result, she no longer needed the support of the Paré Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Dominican_Republic/Charlene.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Charlene&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haiti</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/haiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/haiti/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Haiti/Haiti_Flag.png&#34; style=&#34;float:right;width:150px;height:100px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-paré-scholar-program&#34;&gt;The Paré Scholar Program&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In partnership with the Haitian Education and Leadership Program (HELP), the Foundation has set up a Paré Scholar Program to support deserving young students in Haiti.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started in 2010, shortly after the earthquake, the Paré scholar program consists of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuition-free classes at an internationally accredited university&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Textbooks and supplies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Housing in HELP dorms and a living stipend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic advising and counseling, including computer literacy and English classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership &amp;amp; Citizenship training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on HELP&amp;rsquo;s program, click &lt;a href=&#34;http://uhelp.net/our-story/how-we-work/#sthash.ZRikysiZ.dpuf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our current Paré Scholar, Daana Roc completed her fourth year in a Computer Science degree at the Information Science Institute. Daana achieved an 81% average in her 2018-19 semester; earning herself a place on both the Dean&amp;rsquo;s List and the HELP Honour Roll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Haiti/DaanaRoc.png&#34; alt=&#34;Daana&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Haiti/Daanawithteam.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Team&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very soon we will introduce you to our next Paré Scholar!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/india/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/India/India_Flag.png&#34; style=&#34;width:150px;height:100px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meet-muthazhagi&#34;&gt;Meet Muthazhagi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our collaboration with the Regenboog Foundation continues in Tiruvannamalai where the Paré Foundation is supporting a new student, Muthazhagi, for the final year of her Master&amp;rsquo;s Degree in Medical Physics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/India/IndiaStudent2020.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Muthazhagi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now exploring new ways to support the efforts of the Regenboog Foundation as they work towards establishing an evening school for students who need academic support.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/canada/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Canada/Salluit.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Salluit&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meet-tannis&#34;&gt;Meet Tannis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continue our support of our first Canadian student living in Canada, Tannis, an Indiginous woman who is completing her final semester of a Bachelor of Law from the University of Saskatchewan and is looking forward to graduating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As she looks towards convocation Tannis is focusing on how she can integrate and apply her experiences as an Indigenous woman to help the government and legal systems better support and represent Indigenous issues in Canada and move towards reconciliation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mohawk-language-preservation&#34;&gt;Mohawk Language Preservation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2020, the Paré Foundation will help with living costs for adult students who are training to become teachers of Mohawk language and literacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their living costs are currently severely underfunded and any help will be greatly appreciated.  The adult students, training at Kanehsatake to achieve teaching proficiency in Mohawk, will one day replace the last two current (very elderly) teachers at Kanehsatake Elementary and High School. Most of these adult students have no income stream or financial support to cover living expenses during this training. The support will provide them with the opportunity to help rebuild their traditional language and culture and the capacity to fill these vital positions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
