<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alphonse and Lucy Griffith Paré Foundation</title>
    <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://parefoundation.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Alphonse and Lucy Griffith Paré Foundation</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://parefoundation.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Alphonse and Lucy Griffith Paré Foundation</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malawi</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/malawi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/malawi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-jim-and-nancy-wright-scholars&#34;&gt;The Jim and Nancy Wright Scholars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Led and managed by Antoinette Holland, the Foundation’s agent in Malawi, the program is focused on providing youth, and especially girls, the opportunity to continue their education despite their lack of resources.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jim and Nancy Wright Scholars Program (named in recognition of the Wright family’s long-term support of Antoinette (Toni) Holland’s work, and to honour Jim’s memory) continues to be the model on which new Paré Foundation projects are based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the nature of schooling in Sub-Saharan Africa, the chosen approach is to holistically support beneficiaries, covering both direct and indirect costs of education: tuition fees, textbooks, school supplies, mid-day meals, and transportation costs, if need be. This last item is particularly important when supporting girls’ education, given their vulnerability when traveling long distances in remote areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/ricebags.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rice&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three secondary school Jim and Nancy Wright scholars wrote their end-of-school exams in August and are currently awaiting their results. We hope to continue to support them through university, starting in September 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, here is an update on our current (and recently graduated) university students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Esau (pictured below) graduated with a degree in Land Survey from Polytechnic University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jacqueline graduated with a Bachelor of Science in Development Economics from LUNA (Lilongwe University of Agriculture Research).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Isabelle is studying Earth Science at MUST (Malawi University of Science and Technology) and is currently in the field enjoying her attachment at the Mzuzu Geological Survey Department. In December she will be back in the classroom for her final year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Naomi is at St-Joseph&amp;rsquo;s College of Nursing where she wrote her final exams in May and is now preparing for the nursing license exams at the end of November.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benson completed his year of apprenticeship in electrical engineering and returns to the classroom in January for his final year at Don Bosco Technical Institute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our newest university student, Jane Chiona, is enrolled in a 4 year Bachelor of Arts program in media for development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/Essaugradflowers.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Esau&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;loyola-jesuit-secondary-school&#34;&gt;Loyola Jesuit Secondary School&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our fourth year working in partnership with &lt;a href=&#34;https://loyola-malawi.org/&#34;&gt;Loyola-Malawi&lt;/a&gt;, in memory of Donald Paré, former President of the Paré Foundation, who was deeply committed to the Foundation’s mission, as well as the Jesuit ideal of forming “Women and Men for Others”. We continue to support our first cohort of 5 Paré scholars: four girls, one boy. We are committed to supporting these five students every year through to high school graduation, and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Malawi/loyola-Malawi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Loyola&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loyola-Malawi is a Jesuit run school located in Kasungu district, a few hours north of Lilongwe, the capital. The school boasts beautiful grounds and a new building to welcome its students. Admission is based on merit alone. Run by the Zambia-Malawi Jesuit Province, Loyola strives to offer a ‘preferential option for the poor’* – in this case, high quality education to those that otherwise wouldn’t have access to such schooling. We at the Paré Foundation are thrilled to participate in that mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*The term ‘preferential option for the poor’ is attributed to the Jesuits of Latin America, in the 1960s.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominican Republic</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/dominican_republic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/dominican_republic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Dominican Republic, we supported Charlene for her early elementary education. She attended an international school where she developed her love of learning and gained a lot of confidence socially. However, after 3rd grade, the administrators of the school and her parents agreed that it would be best for her fluency in Spanish to transfer her to a Spanish public school. As a result, she no longer needed the support of the Paré Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Dominican_Republic/Charlene.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Charlene&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haiti</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/haiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/haiti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In partnership with the Haitian Education and Leadership Program (HELP), the Foundation has set up a Paré Scholar Program to support deserving young students in Haiti.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started in 2010, shortly after the earthquake, the Paré scholar program consists of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuition-free classes at an internationally accredited university&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Textbooks and supplies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Housing in HELP dorms and a living stipend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic advising and counseling, including computer literacy and English classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership &amp;amp; Citizenship training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on HELP&amp;rsquo;s program, click &lt;a href=&#34;http://uhelp.net/our-story/how-we-work/#sthash.ZRikysiZ.dpuf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently supporting three Paré Scholars at HELP: Valencia Dorvilus (agro-economics), Sabine Joseph (agro-production), and Katiana Norvil (agro-economics), who is sponsored by the Jind family in Toronto. All three are deeply grateful to HELP for accompanying them in their studies. Academic successes aside, perhaps most important is their commitment to serving their community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valencia, having taken part in the women’s empowerment group at HELP and coordinated the HELP dance club, reports that “…through all these activities, I was able to get involved in my surroundings and use my skills in service of my community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Haiti/valenciaD.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Valencia&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/past-projects/canada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tannis&#34;&gt;Tannis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Paré Foundation supported Tannis, an Indiginous woman, in the completion of her Bachelor of Law from the University of Saskatchewan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Canada/tannis.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tannis&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After graduating in June 2020 amidst the Covid-19 pandemic, Tannis opted to remain in Saskatoon. Going forward, she aims to help alleviate the over representation of Indigenous children in government care. She will be working to help Indigenous communities to implement Bill C-92 which will allow them to direct their own policies to ensure that their children remain within their respective families and communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/india/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our collaboration with the Regenboog Foundation continues in Tiruvannamalai where the Paré Foundation is supporting five students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sakthivel is in his final year of a bachelor degree  in Chemistry. He hopes to work in the Public Service sector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abithagujalambal is in her 2nd year of a degree in Commerce. She hopes to become a chartered accountant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vasanthalagi is in her 3rd year of a degree in Computer Science and is learning Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keerthiga is in her 2nd year, also studying Computer Science.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sujatha is in her 1st year of college. She is doing an internship in a hospital currently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/India/indiaSujatha.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sujatha&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/projects/current-projects/canada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mohawk-language-preservation&#34;&gt;Mohawk Language Preservation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2020, the Paré Foundation supports a Mohawk language program at Kanehsatà:ke, Quebec. The multi-year adult immersion program is offered by the Mohawk Language Custodian Association of Kanehsatà:ke and is designed to ensure the ancestral language survives and flourishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four students graduated at the end of the last session out of a group of six. Interest in the program is growing because the graduates are speaking Mohawk (Kanien&amp;rsquo;kéha) in public, and on the local radio station. That has inspired and motivated others: this year there were twenty-five new applicants, and twenty have been accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the adult students have no income stream or financial support to cover living expenses during their training. While federal funding from Heritage Canada pays for the courses, the Paré Foundation contribution is used to help with the living costs of students who fall short, and it is shared at the discretion of their board. This support motivates the students, who also do local fundraising to cover their expenses, often having given up regular work to meet the demands of the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mohawk Language Custodian Association has also managed to get help from McGill University, which provides access to a teacher training program; fifteen of the twenty new students are participating in both programs. This will help students acquire teaching skills. They will be able to eventually replace the dedicated Elders who have been carrying the project and who are currently teachers at Kanehsatà:ke Elementary and High School.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://parefoundation.github.io/img/Canada/MLP.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mohawk Language Custodian Association&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;carejeunesse&#34;&gt;CareJeunesse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Centre Amitié, Ressources, et Entraide pour la Jeunesse (C.A.R.E. Jeunesse) is a Quebec, bilingual, non-profit organization dedicated to providing a community and a voice for youth leaving government care. Founded by alumni of care who have experienced the system first hand, the organization aims to assist youth after they leave care. The Paré Foundation is offering scholarships to two students who need support to continue their education:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shanice is a student at University du Québec en Abitibi-Témiscamingue, studying Health Sciences. She hopes to become a nurse practitioner and would like
to eventually work in Northern Quebec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elijah is a student at Concordia University in Montreal, doing a certificate of Arts and Sciences and taking additional courses with the School of Community and Public Affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Paré Foundation</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Paré Foundation is a family foundation established by Alphonse Paré and Lucy Griffith’s nine children in 1984.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1984-2005&#34;&gt;1984-2005&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In commemoration of Alphonse and Lucy’s dedication to education, the Foundation was set up to support schools and families in Canada and abroad. In the beginning, it was also active in the area of literary publication and supported the distribution of The Seeds, a family history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2005-present&#34;&gt;2005-Present&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2005, the Paré Foundation’s activities have focused on supporting students in a variety of countries. Currently, the Foundation works with partners and agents in Malawi, Haiti, India, and Canada. The Paré Foundation has also supported short-term projects in Bolivia, Dominican Republic, Israel, and Uganda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-ahead&#34;&gt;Looking ahead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Foundation’s projects center on investing in the education of children and youth, in particular. Given the demand-driven nature of the work of the Foundation, activities tend to vary depending on the needs of the individual student and the country context. The specificities of each investment are determined by the Foundation’s Board of Directors in consultation with the agents managing each project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-back&#34;&gt;Looking back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like more information on the Paré family, take a look at The Seeds, a family history written by Lucy Griffith Paré in collaboration with her son Antoine Paré (published in 1984). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ballyhoo.ca/uploads/2/2/6/9/22695826/the_seeds_searchable.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the book here&lt;/a&gt; (PDF, 178MB). Many thanks to Joe Graham for his help providing online access to this book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board Of Directors</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/bod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/bod/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marie-Claire Holland&lt;/strong&gt; - President&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jane Richards&lt;/strong&gt; - Secretary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marie-Claire Leman&lt;/strong&gt; - Treasurer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter Holland Jr.&lt;/strong&gt; - Communications Coordinator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jane Howlett&lt;/strong&gt; - Membership coordinator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lora Campbell&lt;/strong&gt; - Newsletter Coordinator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joseph Graham&lt;/strong&gt; - Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter Howlett&lt;/strong&gt; - Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Paré&lt;/strong&gt; - Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Julia Paré&lt;/strong&gt; - Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marc Paré&lt;/strong&gt; - Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Victor Paré&lt;/strong&gt; - Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consie Tétrault&lt;/strong&gt; - Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact us at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:parefound@gmail.com&#34;&gt;parefound@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving</title>
      <link>https://parefoundation.github.io/giving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://parefoundation.github.io/giving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;donate-online&#34;&gt;Donate Online&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.canadahelps.org/CharityProfilePage.aspx?CharityID=d12978&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.canadahelps.org/secure/img/Donate1_en.png&#34; alt=&#34;Donate Now Through CanadaHelps.org!&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donations are processed through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.canadahelps.org/en/dn/11145&#34;&gt;CanadaHelps.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;e-transfer&#34;&gt;E-Transfer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are also welcome to send a donation via Interac e-transfer to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:parefound@gmail.com&#34;&gt;parefound@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;donate-by-mail&#34;&gt;Donate by Mail&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please write cheques to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alphonse &amp;amp; Lucy Griffith Paré Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and mail them to the attention of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alphonse and Lucy Griffith Paré Foundation&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
c/o Marie-Claire Paré Holland&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
904-239 Kensington ave&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Westmount, Québec, Canada&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
H3Z 2H1&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
